PANTELIS MANIOTIS

Address: Chelmsford, Essex, UK | Mobile phone: +44 7716651128 | Email: pantmaniotis@gmail.com

Profile:

A competent data engineer/scientist with a comprehensive knowledge and experience in analysing large datasets and developing forecasting models. His fields of knowledge include:

Data Engineering

• Software Engineering

• Time series forecasting

• Relational databases

Machine Learning

• Geospatial Analysis

Database management

• Natural Language Processing

• Reinforcement learning

Please also check my online portfolio for a list of personal projects, publications, etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

CACI

Bata Engineer

Kensington Village, London, UK

Feb 2021 – Now

- Developed ETL data pipelines to provide valuable insights regarding location planning, customer acquisition, and other key business performance metrics.
- Built Machine Learning models for the creation of customer profiles and the grouping of open-ended questions into meaningful classes
- Created interactive dashboards for the reporting of key metrics that were important to the clients.

UNIVERSITY OF ESSEX Wivenhoe Park, Colchester, UK

Data Science / Research and Development

Oct 2016 – Nov 2020

- Simulated 5G mobile networks for the delivery of VR applications, in order to maximise the Quality of Experience users enjoy and minimise the operating cost.
- Extracted valuable insights from the statistical analysis and visualisation of large datasets regarding the users' consumption patterns.
- Developed Machine Learning and Deep Learning models, in order to optimise the performance of the mobile networks.

NDC TECHNOLOGIES

Data AnalystDeveloped a SQL database for data collection and data analysis processes.

Heybridge, Maldon, United Kingdom May 2018 – September 2018

• Built front-end with user menus, input forms, reports, using custom procedures in VBA code and macros to increase consistency of data.

EDUCATION:

UNIVERSITY OF ESSEX

• PhD in Computer Science and Electronic Engineering

Wivenhoe Park, Colchester, Essex, UK October 2016 – November 2020

ARISTOTLE UNIVERSITY of THESSALONIKI (AUTh)

• BSc and MSc in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Thessaloniki, Greece September 2007– April 2015

SKILLS:

• Programming languages / tools: Python, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, GeoPandas, SQLAlchemy,

Tensorflow, Keras, Jupyter, SQL, NoSQL, R, C, C++, VBA, Bash Shell

• Specialized computer software: MS Office, MATLAB, Tableau, Alteryx, SPSS, LaTeX, Adobe Photoshop, GIMP

• Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flask, Django, Bootstrap

• Operating systems: Linux, Windows, Mac OS

• Cloud Computing: AWS (EC2, S3, Glacier, Glue, RDS, DynamoDB, Athena, Elastic Beanstalk,

SageMaker, Lambda, CloudWatch)

• Version Control: GitHub, GitLab